<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>   
    <title>Daniel Fernandez</title>
    <atom:link href="http://dfernandez.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://dfernandez.me</link>
    <description>My personal blog</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 09:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
    <generator>The mighty Wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>China hits Listboard.it</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/China_hits_Listboard.it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 09:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/China_hits_Listboard.it/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I noticed that suddenly &lt;b&gt;many users registered&lt;/b&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt;. First, I thought that it was some sort of spam, but later, site analytics showed me that they were all unique visitors coming mostly &lt;b&gt;from China&lt;/b&gt; thanks &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oschina.net/news/43011/6_codeveloping_over_8300_miles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to an article from oschina.net&lt;/a&gt; that referred our site product. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/article_china.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese article capture&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google translator was a big help here as I know zero Chinese. It helped me &lt;b&gt;dig deeper&lt;/b&gt; and realized that it was not only an article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt;, but one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dfernandez.me/articles/6_Codeveloping_over_8300_miles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my old posts&lt;/a&gt; translated to Chinese. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It said almost the same except for one part that called my attention. I wrote that I used &lt;b&gt;Google Drive&lt;/b&gt; to manage large documents while they wrote that I use &lt;b&gt;Dropbox&lt;/b&gt;. Immediately, I recalled why the did that. Google Drive is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.greatfire.org/https/drive.google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blocked on China&lt;/a&gt;. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also added some sort of picture that was very commented on the site. Not exactly the way I work, but plays well with the article.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a very interesting finding and, well, I cannot complain as &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt; got over &lt;b&gt;200 subscriptions&lt;/b&gt; thanks to it!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-developing over 8,300 miles of distance</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/6_Codeveloping_over_8300_miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 09:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/6_Codeveloping_over_8300_miles/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I tell my friends from Argentina that I am working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt; with a developer from Russia, they ask me &quot;How do you do it?&quot; It is clear why they ask. Denis and I are over &lt;b&gt;8,300 miles&lt;/b&gt; of distance (over &lt;b&gt;13,300 km&lt;/b&gt;), we have our full time jobs and, even worse, we are in completely different time zones. Luckily for us, &lt;b&gt;&quot;developers developed great developing tools&quot;&lt;/b&gt;. What I mean is that current applications to manage and coordinate development are amazing. They make our life so much easier.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are working 2 blocks or thousands of miles away, there is almost no difference. Distance is not a big deal thanks to Internet. That is why all the data we generate for our project (code, notes, documents, stylesheets, pictures, etc) is always kept on the Web. Our tools have access to the Internet and some are directly used from a browser. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, the big challenge is having different time zones. We both have our full time jobs and when I have free time to work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;b&gt;6pm to 11pm my time&lt;/b&gt;), Denis is sleeping (&lt;b&gt;1 am to 5am his time&lt;/b&gt;). Same problem when he codes. We never work both at the same time on the project and yet we manage to perfectly coordinate. We know what each of us is working on, our code is always synced, we have an active communication and we never block each other&apos;s work.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we do that? Well, it is not magic, but only 5 awesome tools. I will not get into much detail on how they work, just mention them:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;: maybe the most important one; we use it to coordinate future, current and finished tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;: helps us save and share large documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bitbucket (git)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;: keeps our code synced, lets us do code review and manage branches per task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Email&lt;/u&gt;: we use it to send updates on what we have worked on or when there is something important to notify the other developer about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skype.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;: although we do not use it that much, whenever we have something that will be too long to discuss by email, we chat 10 minutes on our free time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that it helps a lot that Denis is a great person and we have never had any problem. We both love what we do and are trying to build an excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; application&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested on knowing more about our product or becoming an early tester, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; register&lt;/a&gt;.



&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarking is much more complex than you think</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/5_Bookmarking_is_much_more_complex_than_you_think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 09:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/5_Bookmarking_is_much_more_complex_than_you_think/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long time ago I decided to work on a bookmarking site as a side project. If you are thinking &quot;not another bookmarking site please&quot;, &lt;b&gt;that is good!&lt;/b&gt; It means that you know there are constant new attempts to save/organize/share bookmarks that keep failing. But you may also know that there is still an unsatisfied market. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain why I picked this side project.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many people out there, I constantly deal with the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.williamting.com/posts/2012/10/30/why-we-bookmark/&quot;&gt;three categories of bookmarking&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;b&gt;Now, Later, and Future&lt;/b&gt;. For those who never heard about those categories, here is a quick summary: 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Now&quot;&lt;/b&gt; is for URLs that you are using right &lt;b&gt;now&lt;/b&gt; such as research URLs on your current project, Gmail, etc. (Yes, all those tabs that you have now open!); &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Later&quot;&lt;/b&gt; category represents what you find interesting enough to take a deeper look &lt;b&gt;later&lt;/b&gt; when you have more time available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Future&quot;&lt;/b&gt; are the bookmarks you want to archive/organize to access someday in the long &lt;b&gt;future&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My problem is that I have to use different apps for each category. That makes it really difficult to smoothly move a bookmark from one category to another. If I use Pinboard for later and future bookmarks, I still end up with many opened tabs for what I am working right now.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been long waiting for a solution that properly handles all three of them. But there is none so far (at least that I know). 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that?  We get around two to three new bookmarking sites each month. Why most of them fail? Why some of us are still looking for a way to save their bookmarks?

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even despite anyone trying to create a bookmarking site can find what the &quot;not-yet-satisfied&quot; users want. It is easy. Just perform a quick search and tons of comment and feedback will appear. Here are some from Hacker News:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I mainly want this so that I can organize them (delete, properly name, putting them into different folders, etc) and download them as html.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Apart from cross device availability, please make collaboration easier. Many times I bookmark pages for later market research or sharing it with my coworkers&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;... really simple and good search, RSS for tags, syncing with my bookmarks on all the browsers&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;... letting me save my bookmarks to a bookmark file readable by Firefox&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;They have to shown thats it&apos;s really really easy before they become converts. &quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I can&apos;t be bothered with tagging or confirmation dialogs. I just want to press a single button and have the browser remember it.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I wish there was a program that let you import HTML/JSON files into it from FF, IE, Chrome, Safari, etc then had some good organization features almost exactly like firefox. It should also have the ability to delete duplicate links, organize links, put tags, create folders, etc.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I really want a private bookmarking thing that will: i) Import all my bookmarks.  ii) Gradually crawl images for all those bookmarks. iii) Display everything in a pinterest style grid iv) allow me to drag and drop links around; to add dividers; etc v) allow me to add tags or descriptions etc.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came to the conclution that bookmarking proved to be hard. It is not just about saving some URLs. It is so much more than that. Way more complex than we think it is.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If some new app wants to get that remaining market, something is clear, it has to be disruptive. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/b&gt; If you are interested in knowing more about the solution we are working on to manage bookmarks, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://listboard.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt;. You can even register to become an early tester!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoins in Argentina</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/4_Bitcoins_in_Argentina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/4_Bitcoins_in_Argentina/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:20px;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/bitcoin_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bitcoin logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read about Bitcoin back in 2011, but it was not until this year that I got really involved with it. For those who never heard about Bitcoin, it is just a new currency, like dollars or euros. Some people describe it as a &apos;digital currency&apos; or &apos;crypto-currency&apos;, but I prefer to use only the term &apos;currency&apos; to ease its adoption as suggested in this excellent &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://thegenesisblock.com/five-easy-ways-you-can-make-bitcoin-a-mainstream-currency/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Stacke. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into much details on how it works (I look forward to explain it in future posts), let just say that it operates thanks to the collective power of many connected computers. If you want more details right away, visit &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&apos;s official site&lt;/a&gt; or check this &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Um63OQz3bjo&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Bitcoin is that it is not regulated by any central authority. You can transfer money directly to another person with your computer or mobile. Wow! A non-regulated currency! ... wait, won´t that scare people? No. At least not here in Argentina where we know about regulations. Our goverment regulates the amount of dollars you can buy (regulates, not prohibit), so Bitcoin raises as an insteresting alternative currency.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week ago, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://bitcoinfilm.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoinfilm.org&lt;/a&gt; created a documentary about Bitcoins in Argentina. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/e__m-w4N7NI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video made its way to a major &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.lanacion.com.ar/1575169-bitcoin-como-una-alternativa-a-las-restricciones-cambiarias-en-la-argentina#v_video_&quot;&gt;Argentinian newspaper (spanish)&lt;/a&gt; and I noticed that many friends starting talking about it, asking questions mostly. They were certainly interested in Bitcoin. Besides that, around 100 people assist to last &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Bitcoin-Buenos-Aires/events/110480272/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin MeetUp in Buenos Aires&lt;/a&gt; and it is not crazy to expect that more people will assist to future ones. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are all positive signs. You can tell that Argentina is slowly adopting it. There is still a long path down the road for Bitcoins, but it worth following it.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spread the word!


&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn your browser into a drawpad</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/3%20-%20drawing%20bookmarklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/3%20-%20drawing%20bookmarklet/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not to long ago I came across with an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5135194&quot;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News that proposed to turn your browser into a notepad. The idea was simple; it used the data URI format to include inline HTML and JS. Since that day, I never stop using it. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually picked up an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/danielfrndz/5383435&quot;&gt;improved version&lt;/a&gt; where, when you press CTRL + S keys, it adds the written data to the URL saving it in the browser history for later access.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button_red&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href='data:text/html,&lt;html&gt;&lt;script&gt;window.onload=function(){var a=document.body;a.addEventListener(&quot;keydown&quot;,    function(b){if(b.ctrlKey&amp;&amp;83===b.which){document.location = &quot;data:text/html,&quot; + document.childNodes[0].outerHTML;b.preventDefault();}},!1);document.title= document.body.innerText.replace(/\n[\s\S]+$/,&quot; - &quot;)+new Date().toString();};&lt;/script&gt;&lt;body contenteditable&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
'&gt;Click here to test notepad&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I realized, each of my opened browser windows had a first tab that was using it either for temporal bookmarks or notes. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just love it.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, I was trying to quickly draw something and I asked myself if I could use a similar approach. It turned out that it was possible. You can even save the drawing to the browser history with CTRL + S.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button_red&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href='data:text/html,&lt;html&gt;&lt;style&gt;* { margin:0; padding:0; }html, body {cursor:pointer;width:100%; height:100%; }canvas { display:block; }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;script&gt;window.onload = function() {var myCanvas = document.getElementById(&quot;myCanvas&quot;);var data = document.getElementById(&quot;data&quot;);var curColor = &quot;#000&quot;;if(myCanvas){var isDown = false;var ctx = myCanvas.getContext(&quot;2d&quot;);var canvasX, canvasY;var img = new Image;img.onload = function(){ctx.drawImage(img,0,0);};img.src = data.value;myCanvas.addEventListener(&quot;mousedown&quot;, function(e){isDown = true;ctx.beginPath();canvasX = e.pageX - myCanvas.offsetLeft;canvasY = e.pageY - myCanvas.offsetTop;ctx.moveTo(canvasX, canvasY);}, false);myCanvas.addEventListener(&quot;mousemove&quot;, function(e){if(isDown != false) {canvasX = e.pageX - myCanvas.offsetLeft;canvasY = e.pageY - myCanvas.offsetTop;ctx.lineTo(canvasX, canvasY);ctx.strokeStyle = curColor;ctx.stroke();}}, false);myCanvas.addEventListener(&quot;mouseup&quot;, function(e){isDown = false;ctx.closePath();data.value = myCanvas.toDataURL();}, false);}window.addEventListener(&quot;resize&quot;, resizeCanvas, false);function resizeCanvas() {myCanvas.width = window.innerWidth;myCanvas.height = window.innerHeight;}resizeCanvas();var a=document.body;a.addEventListener(&quot;keydown&quot;, function(b){if(b.ctrlKey&amp;&amp;83===b.which){document.location = &quot;data:text/html,&quot; + document.childNodes[0].outerHTML;b.preventDefault();}}, false);document.title= document.body.innerText.replace(/\n[\s\S]+$/,&quot; - &quot;)+new Date().toString();};&lt;/script&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; id=&quot;data&quot;/&gt;&lt;canvas id=&quot;myCanvas&quot;&gt;Sorry, your browser does not support canvas technology.&lt;/canvas&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;'&gt;Click here to test drawpad&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want to check or improve the code, here it is nicely indented:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/danielfrndz/be5f4d048c24b08ec1dc.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I do not use it as much as the notes, some days I find it very handy.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you too!

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2013 goals</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/2%20-%20goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/2%20-%20goals/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beggining of the year, I set some goals that I want to share with you as a way to formalize them:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my skills with Sublime Text 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct the position of my fingers when typing and reach 50 WPM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have weekly excersice routine and lose 6 kilograms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://listboard.it&quot;&gt;Listboard.it&lt;/a&gt; and reach the first 500 users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn at least one unrelated activity like salsa dance or sailing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch new personal blog and write at least 30 posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create/Colaborate in 3 or more opensources proyects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read at least 4 books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my goals are not that hard to accomplish (well, maybe the 500 users one). The important detail about most of them is that they are measurable: 50 WPm, 6 kilograms, 500 users, 1 activity, 30 posts, 3 opensource proyects, 4 books. I did this on purpose to have some values to compare at the end of the year and then laugh at myself thinking &quot;What the hell was I thinking?&quot;. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, I suggest you do the same and write the goals you want to achieve this year. Do not push your limits, just do it for fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/1-%20welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/1-%20welcome/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I once started a blog and, like many others bloggers, ended up abandoning it. Why is this time going to be any different? Because reasons are different. Now I do it for pleasure. I received so much from the IT community during the last years that I want to start sharing things back. Maybe I can help someone around the world.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I find interesting is that I have more things to share from my last 2 years as a freelancer than from my 10 years of working as a full time Software Engineer in local companies. I will share my experience in future posts for those who are interested in becoming a freelancer, but feel free to contact me if you cannot wait!

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build stuff and enjoy life!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>