<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>   
    <title>Daniel Fernandez</title>
    <atom:link href="http://dfernandez.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://dfernandez.me</link>
    <description>My personal blog</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
    <generator>The mighty Wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>2013 goals</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/2%20-%20goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/2%20-%20goals/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beggining of the year, I set some goals that I want to share with you as a way to formalize them:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my skills with Sublime Text 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct the position of my fingers when typing and reach 50 WPM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have weekly excersice routine and lose 6 kilograms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch &lt;a href=&quot;http://tagnfile.it&quot;&gt;Tagnfile.it&lt;/a&gt; and reach the first 500 users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn at least one unrelated activity like salsa dance or sailing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch new personal blog and write at least 30 posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create/Colaborate in 3 or more opensources proyects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read at least 4 books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my goals are not that hard to accomplish (well, maybe the 500 users one). The important detail about most of them is that they are measurable: 50 WPm, 6 kilograms, 500 users, 1 activity, 30 posts, 3 opensource proyects, 4 books. I did this on purpose to have some values to compare at the end of the year and then laugh at myself thinking &quot;What the hell was I thinking?&quot;. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, I suggest you do the same and write the goals you want to achieve this year. Do not push your limits, just do it for fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://dfernandez.me/articles/1-%20welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dfernandez.me/articles/1-%20welcome/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I once started a blog and, like many others bloggers, ended up abandoning it. Why is this time going to be any different? Because reasons are different. Now I do it for pleasure. I received so much from the IT community during the last years that I want to start sharing things back. Maybe I can help someone around the world.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I find interesting is that I have more things to share from my last 2 years as a freelancer than from my 10 years of working as a full time Software Engineer in local companies. I will share my experience in future posts for those who are interested in becoming a freelancer, but feel free to contact me if you cannot wait!

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build stuff and enjoy life!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>