<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>   
    <title>Daniel Fernandez blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://danielf.com.ar/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://danielf.com.ar</link>
    <description>My personal blog</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
    <generator>The mighty Wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://danielf.com.ar/articles/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielf.com.ar/articles/welcome/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I once started a blog and, like many others bloggers, ended up abandoning it. Why is this time going to be any different? Because reasons are different. I do not want to use it to promote myself and find a good job, but because I received so much from the IT community during the last years that I want to start sharing things back. Maybe I can help someone around the world. As a personal plus, I will improve my post writting skills. Circumstantially, I also feel that I have more things to share now than back then when I was already graduated as a Software Engineer and had over 10 years of experience in developing. I will write a post on this, explaining why I feel that I learned more over my freelancer years when I choosed what to read, than when I was studying Software engenieering in college and working for argentinian sotware companies.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I will end up this first introductory post by sharing my goals for 2013. Writing them here is a way to formalize them. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here they are:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my skills with Sublime Text 2 to develop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correct the position of some typing fingers and reach 50 WPM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach a week excersice routine and lose 6 kilograms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch Tagnfile.it and reach the first 500 users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully migrate to Ubuntu (I still use some windows programs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn at least one unrelated activity like salsa or sailing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch danielf.com.ar blog and write at least 30 posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create at least 3 opensources proyects to share in Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read at leasst 4 books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my goals are not that hard to accomplish (except for the 500 users one), but that is ok. It is the first time I do this and I want to enjoy the path and check results by 2014. What is interesting is that some goals are measurable: 50 WPm, 6 kilograms, 500 users, 30 posts, 3 opensource proyects, 4 books. I did this on purpose to have some values to compare at the end of the year. I suggest you do the same and write the goals you want to achieve this year. Do not push your limits, just do it for fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>